<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ScrollingText</string>
    <string name="article_title">Posthumanism</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">Post-cyborg ethics</string>
    <string name="article_text">In critical theory, the posthuman is a speculative being that represents or seeks to re-conceive the human. It is the object of posthumanist criticism, which critically questions humanism, a branch of humanist philosophy which claims that human nature is a universal state from which the human being emerges; human nature is autonomous, rational, capable of free will, and unified in itself as the apex of existence. Thus, the posthuman position recognizes imperfectability and disunity within oneself, and understands the world through heterogeneous perspectives while seeking to maintain intellectual rigor and dedication to objective observations. Key to this posthuman practice is the ability to fluidly change perspectives and manifest oneself through different identities. The posthuman, for critical theorists of the subject, has an emergent ontology rather than a stable one; in other words, the posthuman is not a singular, defined individual, but rather one who can become or embody different identities and understand the world from multiple, heterogeneous perspectives.\n
\n
Approaches to posthumanism are not homogeneous, and have often being very critical. The term itself is contested, with one of the foremost authors associated with posthumanism, Manuel de Landa, decrying the term as very silly. Covering the ideas of, for example, Robert Pepperells The Posthuman Condition, and Hayless How We Became Posthuman under a single term is distinctly problematic due to these contradictions.\n
\n
The posthuman is roughly synonymous with the cyborg of A Cyborg Manifesto by Donna Haraway. Haraways conception of the cyborg is an ironic take on traditional conceptions of the cyborg that inverts the traditional trope of the cyborg whose presence questions the salient line between humans and robots. Haraways cyborg is in many ways the beta version of the posthuman, as her cyborg theory prompted the issue to be taken up in critical theory. Following Haraway, Hayles, whose work grounds much of the critical posthuman discourse, asserts that liberal humanismвЂ”which separates the mind from the body and thus portrays the body as a shell or vehicle for the mindвЂ”becomes increasingly complicated in the late 20th and 21st centuries because information technology puts the human body in question. Hayles maintains that we must be conscious of information technology advancements while understanding information as disembodied, that is, something which cannot fundamentally replace the human body but can only be incorporated into it and human life practices. en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posthuman
    </string>
    <string name="add_comment">Add comment</string>
</resources>